Well, I’m only 18 years old, as if I didn’t live there
Ну мне только 18 лет я как бы не жил там
in the USSR, nothing. Well, I’m neutral, as if I’m
в СССР ничего Ну я нейтрально как бы я
neither here nor there, that is, well, as if it’s
никак ни там ни сям то есть ну как бы
happening and happening. Well, I live
происходит и происходит Ну вот я живу
calmly, I work, as if life goes on. Everything
спокойно работаю как бы жизнь идёт Всё
to me is like, well, it just turns out I  I see
мене как ну просто получается я я смотрю
that uh how much did I count in short this is uh
что э сколько я считал короче вот это э
How much does one rocket let out Yes it
Сколько одна ракета Да выпускает она
costs to develop and how many of them
стоит на разработку и сколько их
were released then if these money were
выпустили то если бы эти бабки раздать
just distributed to people in the Russian Federation
просто людям в Российской Федерации
everyone would have 20,000 dollars
каждому было бы по 20.000 долларов
estimate
прикинь
Hello guys Great friend I myself come
Привет пацаны Здорово друг Я сам родом
from  Rostov, but I’ve been living in California for 18 years,
из Ростова но уже 18 лет живу в
in 2 years I’ll be
Калифорнии через 2 года будет
20 from Anapa. Krasnodar region of
двадцатое с Анапы Краснодарский кра
Anapa. I know where Anapa is.
Анапа Я знаю где Анапа
Well, once we went on vacation to
Ну когда-то ездили отдыхали в
Gelendzhik
Геленджик
and it’s not really a thrill. Well, damn it, I remember
й не там реально кайф Да ну блин помн
that in short there was darkness for the people. It’s just darkness,
что короче народу была тьма Просто тьма
the feeling that you know they’ve been released  in short, the
ощущение что знаешь выпустили короче
hostel and everyone kind of ran out of
общежитие и все типа выбежали из
it, and what is the difference between California and
него а а чем отличается Калифорния от
Russia and Rostov? Well, it’s very simple Look,
России от Ростова Ну очень просто Смотри
my dad in Rostov now has a pension of
Вот у моего бати в Ростове сейчас пенсия
20,000 rubles, that’s 200 dollars, and in
20.000 руб это 200 долларов а у меня в
California I’m a teacher I teach
Калифорнии Я преподаватель Я преподаю
anthropology at a university My
антропологию в университете У меня
salary is small  9,000 dollars a
зарплата небольшая 9.000 долларов в
month is Russian money 900,000 rubles
месяц это на русские деньги 900.000 руб
by our standards is small because
по нашим меркам небольшая потому что
there is more and you understand and you
есть больше и понимаешь и ты меня
ask me What is the difference between California and
спрашиваешь Чем отличается Калифорния от
Russia, well, as an anthropologist,
России ну а преподаватель антропологи
taxes are big, like you don’t have taxes in
налоги большие типа у вас не налоги в
Russia, by the way, taxes are higher
России кстати налоги больше
Well, in America It’s simpler  will live of
дав Ну в Америке Попроще будет жить
course of course look if uh for example
конечно конечно смотри если э например
here on my salary Yes I
вот на мою зарплату Да я на одну
can buy 5-6 iPhones in
зарплату могу купить 5-6 Айфонов в
Russia with one salary to buy one iPhone Yes
России чтобы купить один iPhone Да
a person needs a job for at least six months Yes
человеку нужна работа полгода минимум Да
and there is nothing conditional Here is a phone We
и не есть ничего условно Вот телефон Мы
can buy easier a car and an American
можем купить проще машина да американец
for less than a month of work, he can easily
за тче месяца работы может себе спокойно
buy a car in Russia, it’s a damn
купить машину в России это блин
teacher to buy a car,
учительница чтобы купила автомобиль се
it’s actually a loan that you can only take out for years. It’s
это вообще это кредит только брать лет
just that when I lived in
на п Просто я когда я когда жил в
Rostov, yes, I also heard taxes there in
Ростове Да я тоже там слышал там в
America, everything, but I had
Америке налоги всё но у меня возник
this problem  the question is why do people from Russia go
такой вопрос почему люди из России едут
to America but don’t go from America to Russia,
в Америку а из Америки в Россию не едут
and those who went there even
да и те кто туда уехали те что даже
talk about how bad it is, everything is
рассказывают Как там плохо там всё
something No one returned, it’s
что-то Никто не вернулся
true, and when I came here to
правда и я когда приехал сюда в
California, I came here first on 2
Калифорнию Я приехал мне сначала на 2
years, they gave me a scholarship to study. I
года дали стипендию для обучения Я
arrived. After 2 months I realized that I
приехал Я через 2 месяца понял что я
had to stay here. I started writing another
должен тут остаться я начал писать ещё
dissertation and extended my
диссертацию и продолжили мне время
stay in the country after defending my
пребывания в стране после защиты
dissertation.
диссертации PHD доктор наук это
simplified
наук то тогда тебе по упрощённой
procedure if you are a scientist, then according to the
процедуре если ты учёный да тогда по
simplified procedure they give you citizenship, that’s
упрощённой процедуре дают гражданство
all well and good, but in general I’ve met
всё ништяк оче а вообще встречал русских
a lot of Russians in California, a lot of them, we
в калифорни много да очень много у нас
have a Russian community. We gather there
есть русская община Мы собираемся там
sometimes in order to
иногда для того чтобы так поща
spend 99,000 dollars.  the
пори 99.000 долларов я вообще это да это
teacher's salary is
блин Это это зарплата преподавателя она
not very big, that is, for example,
не очень большая то есть есть например
if you are a lawyer, yes, or you are a Dentist, like a
если ты юрист да Либо ты Дантист типа
doctor, you get a lot more how to
врач ты намного больше получаешь как
live in nature, send us some money for wallpaper
жить натури скинь нам на обои денег
Well, not me, I send it to my family in Rostov,
Ну не я Я родам своим скидываю в Ростов
you know, I told them, Let's leave, but
знаеш я я им говорил Давайте уезжайте но
Dad won't  Dad wants, you know, lived his whole
батя не хочет батя знаешь прожил всю
life like Here he has friends there
жизнь типа Тут у него там друзья
Acquaintances in short somewhere
Знакомые короче где-то Воспоминания
Childhood memories somewhere he
детства где-то он там с мамкой
met his mother there on these streets Well,
познакомился там на этих улицах Ну
in short, he doesn’t
короче он не
want And who do you
хочет А вы кем работаете
work for? We do internships in college
работаем практику проходим в колледже
now, especially ska tourism
сейчас ну специально ска туризм путёвки
we sell tours like this now from Russia;
продаём так сейчас из России никуда
tours are not sold anywhere in
путёвки не продаются по самой
Russia itself, but where to
России а куда там
go there? Dagestan,
едить Дагестан
some picturesque places, only ate
что-то какие-то живописные только ели
places Well, to go to Dagestan for
места Ну в Дагестан чтобы поехать там по
dentistry, you need to
стоматологии нужно
be
быть
insured. By the way
застрахованным Кстати
[laughter]
[смех]
yes, Baikal is not very far away
да На Байкал далеко то сильно не
on the way to Ana in Gelendzhik around and that's
разъезде куда Ана по Геленжик вокруг и
all I traveled with a tent, the
всё Поездил с палаткой
products in the store are more expensive than in
го ва продукты в магазине дороже чем в
Russia, but there are no products, the products are almost the
России вот нет продук продукты почти
same as in
такие же как и в
Russia and, moreover, the quality. For example,
России и и больше того качество Например
in Russia, if the sausage was pushed there,
у нас в России если колбаса туда походу
Damn, when I  came uh to
на толкали Блин я когда приехал ээ в
California I understood what sausage is.
Калифорнию Я понял что такое колбаса У
We have sausage in Russia, that toilet paper
нас колбаса в Россия та бумага туалетная
there, in short, the bread
там короче хлеб
stuffed the
напихал
bass with a comfortable life, that is, 99,000
баса с комфортом жить то есть 99.000
dollars a month, in fact, you ca
долларов в месяц реально ты можешь себе
n’t deny yourself anything, well, how
по факту ни в чём не отказывать ну как
can you do anything like that?  anyway Well, it
бы можешь ни в чём это всё равно Ну это
seems to you that it’s 99,000 dollars. You won’t
тебе кажется что 99.000 долларов Ты не
refuse anything. For example,
будешь ни в чём отказывать ты например
Russians often say how
вот россияне часто говорят что вот а
much your real estate costs. Yes, for
сколько у вас недвижимость стоит Да они
some reason they compare the Khrushchev house there in
почему-то сравнивают там хрущёвку вот в
our Rostov Yes in California with a
нашем Ростове Да в Калифорнии с
country house because  We have a
загородным домом потому что у нас очень
lot of people in America, we don’t live there in
много в Америке у нас не живут там в
five-story Khrushchev buildings. Yes, we mostly have
пятиэтажках хрущёвка Да у нас в основном
private houses here, and every family
тут частные домики да и у каждой семьи
has a car, at least one of them,
есть машина как минимум одна обы
and my wife also has a
жа и же вот у меня жена тоже имеет
car, she also carries the children. For example, I
машину она детей возит также Например я
drive  children, she vets
везу детей она вет
children, excuse you, your wife is from Russia or
детей извиняй вас жена с России или с
America,
Америки
market Well, she’s such a sweetheart. In short, I
ринка Ну она такая шоколадка Я короче
met her here already, she
познакомился тут уже с нейм
understands a little, But why the hell am I talking to her
немножко понимает Но зачем е это я с ней
in English? Well, yes, yes And children,
по-английски общ Ну да да А дети вот
yes, you have children. Well,  we have children, we have
Дети есть да у вас А ну есть дети у нас
three lingualand, there
три лингвалэнд
may be some shortcomings in California,
какие-то может недостатки в Калифорнии
something Yes, for example, I’m like a person with a stand,
что-то Да например я как человек со стой
I’m used to building some kind of snowman
я привык там какой-то снеговика слепить
there New Year tree Yes, it’s hot here, you’re
там Новый год ёлка Да тут жарко ты тут
walking here Damn, it’s like in Rostov, all the fur coats are
ходишь Блин у нас как в Ростове всё шубы
jackets  you're walking around It's cold and it's winter and here you're
куртки ходишь Холодно да зима а тут ты
walking around in these shorts Yes, I saw
ходишь в этом в шортиках Да вот видел
how Zuckerberg also Yes, everyone started
как Цукерберг также Да всё себе в
wearing shorts there You're driving a car The
шортиках начили там едешь машина
convertible
Кабриолет
drove That is, you don't have winters there at all, how come there's
поехал То есть у вас зимы там не вообще
no such thing, we almost never
нет как такого нет у нас дождей почти не
have rain Cool How about that  you came from Russia
бывает Круто А как вы попали из России
to Yes, the thing is that, look, I’m an
вот в Да дело в том что я смотри я
anthropologist, yes, I graduated from
антрополог да я заканчивал исторический
the Faculty of History
факультет
and majored in
и по специальности
anthropology, and for me it’s very much not
антропология и меня это очень как бы не
such a common profession if you’re a
такая распространённая профессия если ты
specialist, not the
специалист не
leading universities in the world so that you can
ведущие университеты мира чтобы ты у них
write dissertations with them, the university invited me
писал диссертации меня пригласил
Sacramento University from
университет Сакраменто университет из
Zurich and the University of Skos Well, of course I
цюриха и университет скос Ну я конечно
chose Sacramento, it’s in California and I didn’t
выбрал Сакраменто это в Калифорнии и не
regret it, after all, you know the beach Well,
пожалел всё-таки знаешь пляж Ну
yes And how much is your
да А у вас сколько
salary? Well, how much am I now, let’s
зарплаты Ну сколько вот я я сейчас
say I’ll work as a waiter in the same
работу допустим официантом тем же в
hotel in Chad 2600 shift as fast as 22 there
отеле в чедом 2600 смена скоко 22 там
it comes out to 40-45 thousand Well, I also have 22
выходит тысяч 40-45 Ну у меня тоже 22
only 2800 already so well 22 that’s two you
только 2800 уже так ну 22 это два
work two you rest yes dada yes yes And
работаешь два отдыхаешь да дада да да И
how much do you get per month Well here I am 45
сколько получаешь в месяц Ну вот я 45
somewhere you’re like about fifty dollars 50 50
где-то ты сколько под полтинник 50 50 с
something like fifty dollars how much  this is 500
чем-то под полтинник сколько это 500
dollars Yes, roughly speaking, yes, well, like for
долларов Да грубо говоря да ну типа для
beginners. Well, for Russia, it’s not bad, you
начинающих Так ну для России неплохо
can buy yourself some kind of hot dog,
можно какой-то там ну хот-дога себе
in short, somewhere there, well, too, and
купить короче где-то там ну тоже да
put it aside somewhere else with a girl,
отложить ещё там се где-то с девушкой
go to something like this, for example
сходить типа там например
anyway, it’s still not enough to go to
это всё равно не хватает как-то в
America better in America Well, yes But
Америку получше в Америке Ну да А вот
how about the
как
car you have, what kind of car you have And we understand you Well, we’re
какая автовас А понял у нас вас Ну мы
kind of like mo Listen, but I
как как бы как мо Слушай а как вот я
just haven’t been to this in Russia for 18 years
просто 18 лет уже не был в это в России
because I left, I didn’t come
потому что я как уехал я не приезжал У
My parents came here to
меня родители приезжали сюда ко мне в
visit me Yes, I didn’t come somehow it doesn’t work at all It’s as
гости Да я не приезжал как-то вообще не
calm as now for you there,
тянет У вас там как сейчас спокойно ти
these shellings aren’t going on Well, no,
не идут эти обстрелы какие-то А ну нет
why was there shelling in Novorossiysk  We are
почему в Новороссийске был обстрел у нас
very much in Anapa, too, there are fires and something
прям очень в Анапе тоже пожары и что-то
flew there, too, well, to Anapa. Well, we didn’t
прилетало туда тоже ну в Анапу Ну мы не
hear. What we heard about the arrival in
слышали Что прилета мы слышали в
Novorossiysk was tough. The arrival in Anapa
Новороссийск жёсткий был Прилёт в Анапе
was not there. A couple of drones flew in, not
не было там Наро пару Дронов прилетело
even a couple there; it would be really cruel, but
даже не пару там пря жесточайший бы а
how are people in general  Everyone feels differently about this
как люди вообще относятся к этой
war, as if they live in
войне все по-разному как бы коне живут в
Russia, but they live in Russia. They can’t
России но они живут в России Они не
seem to be against it. Well, it’s not like they’re
могут как бы быть против Ну не то что
against the war. Yes, they can’t be against
против войны Да они не могут быть против
their own country where they live. Well, what do
своей же страны где они живут Да ну что
I have, for example?  I have a mother who
у меня например у меня мам которая
says that Putin calls him with these words
говорит что Путин такими словами его
he started a war of sleep Dad, he
называет развязал войну сна Батя он
went for Putin and voted for him. He’s like, you
ходил за Путина голосовал Он такой типа
know, stubborn. In short, I’m like, well, it’s
знаешь упоротый Короче у меня типа ну
clear. Well, well, well, here I am. Well, I’m
понятно Ну ну вот ну вот я как Да ну мне
only 18 years old, it’s as if I didn’t live there  nothing in the USSR
только 18 лет я как бы не жил там в СССР
Well, I’m neutral, as if I’m neither
ничего Ну я нейтрально как бы я никак ни
here nor there, that is, well, it’s like it’s happening
там ни сям то есть ну как бы происходит
and it’s happening Well, I live calmly, I
и происходит Ну вот я живу спокойно
work, as if life goes on. Everything just
работаю как бы жизнь идёт Всё просто
turns out, I see that as much as I thought,
получается я смотрю что сколько я считал
in short, this is how much one rocket Yes,
короче вот это сколько одна ракета Да
it fires  it costs to develop and
выпускает она стоит на разработку и
how many of them were produced, then if these
сколько их выпустили то если бы эти
money were simply distributed to people in the Russian
бабки раздать просто людям в Российской
Federation, everyone would have 20,000
Федерации каждому было бы по 20.000
dollars.
долларов
Estimate that they spent so much on the war on the war
Прикинь на войну на войну потратили
that everyone, if this money was not
столько чтоб каждому если эти деньги не
used in missiles, not in shells Yes, but
в ракеты не в снаряды пустили Да а
simply distributed to the residents of the Russian Federation Yes  everyone
просто раздали жителям РФ Да каждый
would receive 20 grand bucks
получил бы по 20 штук баксов
Just think, and I’m just so surprised
Прикинь да и просто я я так удивлён Да
Yes, when I moved to California, I realized But
вот когда в Калифорнию переехал я понял
then I traveled to other
По путешествовал потом ещё по другим
countries and I see that Russia We have
странам и смотрю что Россия У нас есть
oil, gold, gas, diamonds,
нефть золото газ алмазы
and the standard of living is simply
а уровень жизни просто
possibly being stolen because it’s a plus  those who steal are
возможно воруют потому что плюсом воруют
those who sit in positions of civil servants
те кто сидят на должностях госслужащие
Yes, our brothers deputies are our deputies. Well, who allows them to
наши депутаты Ну а кто им позволяет
steal
воровать
then? Well, someone allows it, it’s
тогда Ну вот позволяет кто-то же за этим
watching everything. It’s
следит за всем Это ж
not like Putin doesn’t travel and well, he
не как бы Путин же не ездит и ну не
can’t physically travel and control
может физически ездить и контролировать
all budgets  they were allocated a budget they
все бюджеты им бюджет выделили они его
stole it someone should
разворовали кто-то же должен
control this budget But who
контролировать бюджет этот А вот кто А
But well, we don’t know who is doing it anymore they have
вот ну мы не знаем уже кто это делает
their own system they have their own some kind of
уних своя система у них своя какая-то
system it turns out I’m right Well,
система получается я я правильно Ну
just your opinion, that is,
просто вот ваше мнение то есть виноваты
which ones are to blame  -the deputies but not the Supreme Power
какие-то депутаты но не Верховная власть
Putin is not to blame, it turns out the Supreme
Путин не виноват выходит Верховная
Power should also control all this,
власть тоже должна это всё
but there seems to be some kind of
контролировать но там какой-то видимо
conspiracy. If it’s not controlled,
сговор Если как бы это не контролируется
then there is money that should go to
то есть деньги которые должны идти на
playgrounds, to schools, to hospitals,
детские площадки там на школы на больниц
as if that’s all  it’s done But it
так как бы оно всё делается Но это
’s made from bad materials That is,
делается из плохих материалов То есть
part of it is stolen and part of it is run on that
часть ворует а часть запускается на то
is, well, they do everything very badly but things are done I
есть ну очень всё плохо делают но дела В
mean, part of it is launched
смысле часть запускается
on labor
на рабочая
force as it were So wait stop stop
сила как бы это Так подожди стоп стоп
stop you get 450 dollars a month as a waiter
стоп ты получаешь в месяц официантом 450
and
долларов и
tyri labor
тыри рабочая
force  The EU takes the speed that works
сила ЕС брать быстроте которые работают
good money, here is the salary of Builders and
хорошие деньги вот зарплата Строителей и
Well, of course they are paid less than
Ну конечно им меньше платят чем вот
hiring Builders, they will make it
нанять Строителей подороже они сделают
more expensive, not just that you’re so funny,
качественней не просто ты так прикольно
you said before that you
на ты перед этим говорил что ты
get 45,000 rubles Yes,
получаешь 45.000 руб Да в месяц
working as a waiter a month Yes, two turns, that is,
официантом работая Да два черед то есть
450  dollars and you
450 долларов и ты
say the labor force is that Dude, you
говоришь рабочая сила та Чувак ты
labor force is really me too little Yes, I’m
рабочая сила реально ме тоже мало Да
still making money, but it’s like I’m not really
пока зарабатываю но как бы особо не
straining either, I don’t have settings, I don’t
напрягаясь тоже я не вхи настройки не
carry bricks, I don’t mix cement there, I
таскают кирпичи цемент там не замешиваю
mean, I have three meals a
я то есть у меня три раза приём пищи в
day, as if I  I work, that is, really
день как бы я работаю ну то есть реально
without stress, and they don’t eat three times a day, yes,
без напряга а не едят три раза в день да
not a fact. And who said they, they eat
а не факт А кто сказал они ж они же едят
it either for their money or it is
это либо за свои бабки либо им
provided to them. Do you mean that they
предоставляют А ты имеешь в виду что
feed you three times a day, yes yes, me
тебя кормят три раза в день да да Меня
exactly  they feed me as if I’m not they are
именно кормят как бы я не они
straining And their work is much
напрягаются А у них работа намного
harder than mine and they get paid Well,
тяжелее чем моя и получают они Ну
let’s say the same money Uh-huh, I understand,
допустим те же самые деньги Угу понял
interesting yes And you have a lot of all sorts of
интересно да А много у вас там всяких
Tajiks and Uzbeks there Yes, well,
таджиков узбеков Да ну вот у меня лично
at my work personally I have Uzbeks working at the car wash
на работе У меня на мойке работают
in general, it’s like we’re building a
узбеки вообще все как бы у нас строится
hostel in a hotel just for workers, also
общага в отеле прям для работников тоже
construction is underway, Uzbeks are also working, but
стройка идёт узбеки тоже работают но они
today was their last day of work and they
вот сегодня последний день работали и
fired all of them, now they’ll all go
уволили всех их они сейчас все поедут
home to their homeland, well, without Well,
домой к себе на родину ну без Ну скорее
most likely because there are simply no people anymore  the
всего потому что людей просто нету уже
season is over, they were hired mainly for the
сезон закончился их брали в основном на
season when the influx of people is at its peak. So
сезон когда наплыв людей самый идёт Вот
they seem to be right in. That is,
они как бы прям впа То есть у нас
let’s say we have an Uzbek girl at work,
допустим узбечка есть на работе девушка
and she’s one for three, that is,
да она одна за троих то есть работает
she works on sinks and floors, that is, she washes and
она и на мойки и полы то есть Моет и
tidies everywhere and  she cuts fruit, that is,
прибирает везде и фрукты режет то есть
well, she seems to be doing the work for three people
ну она как бы делает за троих работу
alone, but I don’t understand. But in Russia,
одна а я не понял А что вот в России же
too, we have a lot of people living in villages
тоже есть у нас много в деревнях живут
who could work, but they don’t
люди которые могли бы работать что их не
hire them to work, maybe they
берут работать может они
just exist like that Yes, there is downtime,
просто есть такие Да есть простоя
yes  yes, well, absolutely, in general, I agree here, I
да да ну как бы безусловно вообще тут я
know we also have a family here in California.
соглашусь я знаю у нас тут в Калифорнии
Well, in our neighborhood
есть тоже э семья Ну в квартале у нас
there, they are from Uzbekistan and they really are
там то они из Узбекистана и они реально
constantly working two
они постоянно они работают на двух
jobs, then in short, they also do it at home. They are
работах потом короче они ещё дома делают
constantly there  everything is well-groomed, they
Там постоянно у них всё ухожено
cut their hair short, they are generally handsome Yes, the Uzbeks are not hard-working here in Russia, like they go to the village there, everything is life in the village, everything is life Yes, that’s all, but in Uzbekistan, I broke up with them No, they
а Узбекистана я с ними раскал Нет они
do spin around somehow they go to work
делают крутятся как-то едут на заработки
Well, here I have Uzbeks  they work, they don’t
Да ну вот у меня вот узбеки работают не
drink, they don’t smoke at all, no one That is, everyone
пьют не курят вообще никто То есть все
who is there and how many
кто есть там да сколько там ме ну
people are there 20 Yes, they work in a hotel, they don’t drink or
человек 20 Да работает в отеле не пьёт и
smoke at all, no one all works, they
не курит вообще никто все работают они
just whine and that’s it Listen, what do you
только вхи и вс Слушай а как вот вы вы
think? Here you are young guys How  Do you
считаете Вот вы молодые парни Как вы
think that’s why the war started?
считаете из-за чего война началась Вот э
I don’t remember when the shelling took place, I don’t remember in the
когда шли обстрелы я не помню по-моему в
Lugansk region, but somewhere there,
Луганской области да где-то ж там 10 лет
Ukraine shelled for 10 years because they
Украина обстреливала потому что они
separated from Ukraine and became, as it were, a
отсоединили от Украины стали как бы
separate part, because of this they were
отдельной частью из-за этого их
shelled constantly  Russia decided to
обстреливали постоянно Россия решила это
fix it. Well, they sort of fixed it, but in the
исправить Ну и как бы исправили это и но
end we didn’t stop there, we
по итогу мы не остановились на этом мы
went further to Ukraine. Well, I don’t
пошли дальше на Украину я Ну я не
understand why
понимаю зачем
and what they fixed, for example, look, Russia
а что исправили например смотри Россия
destroyed Mariupol, destroyed the city of
уничтожила Мариуполь уничтожила город
Bakhmut in the Donetsk region. Yes, for example,
бахмут в Донецкой области Да например
solidar in the Donetsk region  what is she
солидар в Донецкой области что же она
there with if they tell me I just
там с вот если мне мне говорят Просто я
wasn’t there but I watched they say that
не был там да но я смотрел говорят что
Ukraine shelled Donetsk for 8 years Donetsk
Украина обстреливала Донецк 8 лет Донецк
everything is functioning there people live
всё там функционирует люди живут
trolleybuses go Yes trams and people
троллейбусы ходят Да трамваи и люди
go to schools and so on Russia came and
ходят в школы и так дальше Россия пришла
liberated Bakhmut stupidly Ruins  it’s just that
освободила бахмут тупо Руины просто
the ruins of more than one living person are not there,
Руины не одного живого человека нет ну
well, well, that’s how it turned out,
как бы ну вот получилось как получилось
maybe you know better there Like you’re from
просто Может вам там виднее Типа вы из
Russia Yes, I can’t understand that if
России Да я не могу понять что если
Russia came to protect the people in Bakhmut and
Россия пришла защитить людей в бахмуте и
all of them Well, the
всех Ну вот
investigation is stuck and has developed everything is
следствие зависла о развила всё всё
fine the investigation  Well, the consequence is that it’s
нормально следствие чего Ну следствие
like a war started, it
как бы война как бы пошла всё это же
was all a special military operation, and in the
была специальная военная операция сво по
end it all turned into a war. We didn’t come.
итогу всё переросло в войну Мы пришли не
Why was there a special operation at all?
А зачем зачем это спецоперация вообще
I can’t, well, just like
была я что-то не могу вот да неск
Lugansk, this is Ukraine. Let Ukraine
Луганск - это Украина Пусть Украина
deal with it.  nymph Well, in general, yes, but there
разбирается с нимфа Ну вообще да но там
were defenseless people there were shelling
люди беззащитные были обстрелы шли
just as if they had nothing to do, we
просто как бы им делать было нечего мы
decided to protect them Well, this is how I understood it,
решили их защитить Ну это как я понял
judging by the on I just can’t
это вот Судя по на Я просто не могу
understand. Now, if we wanted to protect them,
понять Вот если бы мы хотели их защитить
we would have taken and protected them, yes  Or we
мы бы взяли и защитили да Или мы
invited the UN so that the troops would stand up and
пригласили ООН чтобы войска он встали и
protect them then everything was and so we
защитили их тогда всё было а так мы
went in and took the territory of Donetsk
зашли и забрали территорию Донецка
Lugansk and said that this is our Russia
Луганска и сказали что это наша Россия
now this is not protection Well, that’s how it
теперь это не защита Ну вот так как-то
went, apparently up there people have a different opinion in
пошло видимо там наверху другое мнение у
general.  for example, I’m
людей вообще у нас например вот я ж
watching American news, but
американские новости смотрю да что
Ukraine has been suggesting all these years that
Украина Все эти года типа предлагала
the Peacekeepers go there to Donetsk
чтобы Миротворцы он зашли туда на Донецк
Lugansk so that there is control so that there are no
Луганск чтобы был контроль чтобы не было
Russian troops, and so on. Then Yes, and then, like, Russia
российских войск и так Дальше Да А тут
gets it,
типа получает
Russia blocked this decision at the UN all the years,
Россия блокировала в ООН все года это
and then it decided  like to protect And the
решение А тут решила типа защитить И
defense took it for themselves, it’s unclear Well,
забрала это себе защита непонятно Ну да
by the way, it’s all Russia now,
кстати это ж теперь всё Россия
Lugansk Donetsk, it’s all
получается Луганск Донецк это же всё к
now
России теперь
transferred to Russia, and what does it have to do with it, look You know what’s
перешло причём причём смотри Знаешь что
most
самое
interesting Our Russia cannot
интересно Наша Россия не может
provide housing Yes, they tell us that housing
обеспечить жильём Да вот нам говорят вот
has been built there in Mariupol, yes  for the
в Мариуполе отстроили там жильё да для
people there, they built one house, rented
людей там по один дом построили сняли
it from all sides And everything in Anapa,
его со всех сторон И всё у вас в Анапе
in short, they build housing for you and distribute it
короче строят для вас жильё и раздают
no no yes that’s the question Yes why why
нет нет да то то вопрос Да почему почему
uh my dad and mom Yes in Rostov they have a
ээ мой батя с мамой Да в Ростове они на
hunchbacked brother who lives in their apartment  now in
горбатий брат который живёт сейчас в
Rostov He, by the way, works at a car wash,
Ростове Он кстати на автомойке работает
yes, it’s me who became a scientist Yes, why does he
да это я в учёного Пошёл Да он почему он
have to earn shelter for an
себе должен заработать кров пом на
apartment, and the dude in Donetsk, Lugansk,
квартиру да а чувака в Донецке Луганске
like they give out apartments here like free of charge, it’s
типа выдают тут квартиры типа бесплат
absolutely amazing True Well, yes, of course
вообще [__] Правда Ну это да Конечно
they They are a little more  Here in
они Они е они ещё немножко Вот у нас в
Rostov my mother also told me that
Ростове мамка рассказывала тоже да по
these people came from Donetsk and Lugansk,
приезжали эти из Донецка Луганска типа
they are like refugees. Yes, they are right, they download a
беженцы они Да они права качают у них
Ukrainian passport. Yes,
паспорт украинский есть Да они
Ukrainians can travel to Europe, they
украинскому могут ездить в Европу они
come as Ukrainians, they receive
приезжают как украинцы Они получают там
benefits there, they come to Russia, they are registered
пособие приезжают в Россию оформляются
here as refugees here.  allowance
тут как беженцы тут пособие
Estimate Yes, well, by the way, this is somehow
Прикинь Да ну это кстати как-то
wrong because it’s as if they are given
неправильно потому что как будто им дают
more than we ourselves, we live here,
больше чем нам же самим мы здесь живём
yes, yes it turns out And my mother says
да да получается И мамка моя говорит
Damn, there’s an employee at her work Yes,
Блин вот у неё на работе э сотрудница Да
she’s from Donetsk Yes,
она сама из Донецка Да
she’s with a Ukrainian passport  went
она с украинским паспортом она поехала
somewhere to Europe, registered as a refugee,
где-то в Европу оформилась как беженка
and then came and worked in Russia in
Да и приехала дальше работает в России в
Rostov, she receives more from Russia, in short,
Ростове получает ещё от России короче
in addition to the salary, she receives benefits like a
кроме зарплаты получает пособие как
refugee from Donetsk, think about it And my mother
беженка из Донецка прикинь И мамка
says, Look, I’m plowing getting a salary and
говорит Смотри я пашу получаю зарплату а
she’s getting a salary, receiving benefits
она получает зарплату получает пособие
from Russia, receiving benefits  from the
от России получает пособие от
European Union
Евросоюза
Think about it and they still In short, they don’t tear away
Прикинь и и они ещё Короче не отрывают
that we Russia owe them
что мы Россия им должны
these, of
вот такие вот
course And what is it like in California? Yes, you
конечно А какая у вас в Калифорнии Да вы
live in the city of Sacramento, California,
живёте город Сакраменто штат Калифорния
this is the state of California, what kind of job have you seen or
вот штат Калифорния какую Вы видели или
heard of the highest paying
слышали самую высокооплачиваемую именно
job? Well, look here the question is  that not
работу Ну смотри тут вопрос в том что не
everyone shines with their salary, yes Well,
все светят своей зарплатой да Ну
for example, I have a friend N He is a
например вот у меня есть знакомый Н он
lawyer lawyer Yes, he is a lawyer in, let’s say, we
юрист юрист Да он юрист в скажем у нас
have several
вот есть в городе Сакраменто несколько
such top law firms in the city of Sacramento He is
таких топовых адвокатских компаний Он
included in his company is called Johnson
входит его компания называется Johnson
and partners, uh, it is in the top 3  that
and partners ээ она входит в топ-3 то
is, in the top 3 he receives $16,000
есть в топ-3 он получает 16.000 долларов
a
в
month. Well, he’s a lawyer, he’s a lawyer, that is,
месяц Ну это юрист это юрист он то есть
with us it’s very much valued, if you’re a lawyer,
у нас это очень ценится если ты юрист
that’s all, but
шаришь то всё а
in the top one, the prices there are generally
в топ оди то там вообще цены
prohibitive. Well, you
запредельные Ну они соответственно
know, they’re not just any household stuff there  problems
знаешь там не какие-то бытовые проблемы
are solved Well, yes Yes, that’s understandable And then
решают Ну да Да это понятно А тут же
California is the Valley of Startups,
Калифорния это Долина стартапов
it’s a hell of a lot, so And in this, we
тут капец всего так что А в этом в
were in New York, not in New York, it’s not like damn it, you don’t want to
нью-йорке были не в нью-йорке не это
fly across the whole country, you don’t
блин через всю страну летать что-то не
want to be here in New York, it’s cold there, it’s damn it
хочется тут ньюйорк там холодно это блин
almost damn near Canada, in short, it’s warm here, the
почти блин под Канадой короче тут тепло
beach, if only you’d stayed in California,
пляж ты если бы Побыл в Калифорнии ты
where would you like to go? Which New York would you like?
куда какой нью-йорк бы хотел Ты что
Why fly there, in short, like, there
зачем туда лететь тут короче как что тут
are girls here, there are beaches, there are
есть девушки есть пляжи есть короче
fruits, whatever you want to eat, eat in shorts
фрукты какие хочешь есть есть в шортиках
in a convertible, go damn it yourself  to
на кабриолете едешь блин себе в
teach at the university I remember
университет преподавать Я как вспомню
how I studied in Rostov Damn, we have these
как Я учился в Ростовском Блин у нас эти
teachers, in short, he’s getting a
преподы короче он при
living, well, really, yes How do you look KATO is
пожива ну реально да Как смотришь КАТО
going, in short, some type of yes, he’s a
идт короче какой-то типа да нему это
university teacher And then
преподаватель университета А тут
the teacher you come shirt in
преподаватель ты приезжаешь рубашечка в
Galstena
Галстена
[music]
[музыка]
seriously not  I’m not a fan of these films, what
серьёзно не я не фанат этих фильмов что
happened to the boy on the street to the
с пацаном случилось ул в
toilet
туалет
No, I heard the salary
Нет услышал зарплату
ri, you can get normal money, these are the
ри можно нормально бабок получить это
settings if you work for the customer yourself, then you
настройки если на заказчика самому
can
работать то там можно
earn a tool there without anything, my
заработать инструмента без ничего у меня
shift was from 5,000 rubles, then it was not
смена была от 5.000 руб вот тогда было
bad Not well, if you are  you get
неплохо Не ну если вы вот получаете
99,000 dollars a month Yes, 900,000
99.000 долларов в месяц Да 900.000
Russian rubles rubles Yes, in order to
российских рублей рублей Да у нас чтобы
receive that much money in Russia per month, you need to
получать столько денег в России в месяц
have one Well, well
иметь причём Неплохо
promoted, it’s not bad to get 9000 in Russia
раскрученный неплохо получать в России
I laughed l
9000 я посмеялся л
it’s just for a month this That is, not at
это просто за месяц это То есть ни на
any official job somewhere  You won’t
одной официальной где-то работе Ты не
get that kind of money at all in any job, no matter what the
получишь такие деньги вообще ни на одной
position
просто Какая бы там должность не
is. Even if you’re a director somewhere in a
была Даже если ты где-то директор в
company, but you can’t, you won’t
компании но ты ты не можешь ты не будешь
receive 900,000 rubles a month,
там получать 900.000 в месяц рублей
in general, the expenses are about the same. By the way,
вообще расходы примерно одинаковы Кстати
what about you?  to the prices of
а у вас Кстати что по ценам на
gasoline,
бензин перем
they say the prices of gasoline Yes, this is
они говорят цены на бензин Да это у нас
gasoline in gallons. Yes, we get
же в галлонах бензин Да у нас получается
gasoline that is about 20% only more expensive
бензин где-то на 20% всего лишь дороже
than in Russia, if so, then high-quality
чем в России если так и то качественный
gasoline, yes. And in some States it is the same
бензин да А в некоторых Штатах такой же
as in  Russia and that's it Well, somewhere around 70 in
как и в России и всё Ну где-то 70 в в
America there is just darkness of oil America is one
Америке нефти просто тьма Америка один
of the largest exporters of
из самых больших экспортёров
oil, but some of you have colossal
нефти а вот какие-то у вас колоссальные
colossal differences in prices, that
колоссальная вот разница в ценах есть То
is, what in Russia costs so much in
есть то что в России стоит столько в
America costs much more than that  Is
Америке прям намного стоит дороже что
this or is there no such thing, that that that I do
это или такого нету прям что что прям
n’t even know what In short, we could
даже не знаю что Короче у нас можно было
only have something like this from Russia We
б такое разве что что-то что из России
need to bring I don’t know Kato Damn
Нужно привести Я не знаю Като Блин зуб
Maman’s tooth is already frozen, dug up
Маман там уже замороженный выкопанный
somewhere there and medicine is expensive Uva And
где-то там а медицина дорогая Ува А
by the way  We have insurance through medicine. The thing is,
кстати медицина у нас по страховки Дело
look, while I was living in Rostov, I
в том что смотри пока я жил в Ростове Я
thought that we had free medicine
думал что у нас бесплатная медицина
when I came to California, I realized that
когда я приехал в калифор я Поня что у
we simply don’t have medicine in Russia. Yes, they’ll give you a
нас в России медицины просто нет Да тебе
free injection for that. Yes, they’ll
за это бесплатно короче дадут укол Да
give you a damn pill.
дадут короче блин таблетку глюконат
Calcium gluconate is shorter and the nurse will pat
кальция короче и медсестра погладит по
you on the shoulders and, like, everything in America Yes,
плечи тебя да типа и всё в Америке Да
medicine is expensive But there is insurance You
медицина дорогая Но есть страховки Ты
pay insurance and insurance
платишь страховку да и страховка
covers these costs and that’s it, and there are
покрывает вот эти издержки и всё и
also private clinics, you know,
частные клиники также есть понимаешь
insurance rush
страховая порыва
insurance How much does insurance cost
страховка Сколько стоит страховка стоит
if it works out per month  per month 300
если в месяц получается в месяц 300
dollars and well, 300,000 rubles is calculated Well, out of
долларов а ну 300.000 руб счита Ну из
9,000 dollars Yes, 300 can be given away Well, yes, yes
9.000 долларов Да 300 можно отдать Ну да
But no, it’s 30,000 rubles per month 30,000
да А нет это 30.000 руб в месяц 30.000
rubles, yes, 30,000 rubles comes out per month, but at the
руб да 30.000 руб выходит в месяц но при
same time, if there is something there, well, it’s out of 900, yes that
этом если там что-то ну это из 900 да то
is  you understand, that is, if you
есть понимаешь то есть если
look at a person in Russia, 300
смотреть для человека в российс 300
dollars insurance is something, yes, if you
долларов страховку это что-то да если ты
say out of 9,300 you give it a completely
говоришь из 9 300 даёшь это совсем
different truth Yes yes it is So
другое правда Да да так и есть Так что
yes and more than that if you look Yes
да и больше того если смотреть Да
life expectancy in the USA is
продолжительность жизни в США
higher not nus  This doesn’t allow us to do this.
выше не нус у нас такого не допускает
What, for example, in Russia, can someone like work
Что например как в России может работать
in a hazardous enterprise? Yes,
типа на вредном предприятии Да сверх
breathe beyond the norm, in short, there are these exhausts;
нормы дышать короче там выхлопы эти
do everything here seriously. You, like,
делать тут всё серьёзно Ты если типа
dump Waste into the river Yes, Tomorrow the
будешь сливать Отбросы в речку Да Завтра
enterprise will be closed. Let’s go to America,
же закроют предприятие Поехали в Америку
let’s get us a visa. How?  So it
давайте вы нам визу сделали А как вот
turns out that you need to get a visa and in order to get
получается надо делать визу и чтобы
from Russia from Russia now to
сейчас из России из России сейчас чтобы
get to America you have to go through Turkey Yes, you have to
попасть в Америку надо через Турцию Да
go directly because I don’t
ехать потому что напрямую не знаю как
know how to do it now, I don’t know how to
сейчас вообще не знаю как сейчас
get it now Yes,
получить Да каким-то
somehow you still have to
образом надо вже ещё каким-то образом
get it in some other way, well, with  your
получить ну с вашим
education is just to
образованием разве что через
get across the Mexican border. If
мексиканскую границу пробираться Если
it works out, then then
получится да тогда потом
[laughter]
[смех]
I’ll do time to get married and give birth to the whole child as an
отсижу пожениться и всё ребёнка родить
American girl, yes Question What are you really for? By the way, Kiri I know what an American girl is for. Yes, she earns
девочка американка Да зарабатывает там
$8,000 there. Yes, for example. Yes, no, hey
8.000 долларов Да например Да не ну хи у
Look at her, she has uh boyfriends here,
неё смотри у неё есть ээ ухажёры тут
in short, from America Yes, who
короче из Америки Да которые
earn 91 and thousand dollars, and here,
зарабатывают 91 да тысяч долларов и тут
in short, Kirill from Anapa says Hey baby
короче Кирилл из Анапы говорит Эй беби
Hello I want an American Girl she's like that And how did you
Hello Я хотеть American Girl она така с
find out my name Yes, what did he say
А как ты моё имя Узнал да что он сказал
kikha said and you said
киха сказал а ты сказал
and Kirill Kirill, of course, I couldn’t say
а Кирилл Кирилл не я конечно мог сказать
I’m
Я
a psychic 18 years of practice in 2 years
экстрасенс 18 лет практики через 2 года
it will be the twentieth said Kiryukha Yes And you,
будет двадцатого сказал Кирюха Да А вы
that is, from America to Russia at all, yes don’t
то есть с Америки в в Россию вообще да
Go to I don’t even want to I don’t even
не Собирайтесь во даже не хочу Даже не
want to I have a fear that the borders will be closed
хочу У меня есть страх что закроют
I’ll stay  in Russia
границы я останусь в России
forever the mentality is different in general different
навсегда менталитет разный вообще разный
in general the mentality is generally different yes the
вообще менталитет вообще разный да
Americans are good-natured Yes they smile
американцы Добродушные Да улыбаются
all the time, all the time Yes you
постоянно вот постоянно Да ты куда бы не
come wherever you come in Russia You come as if you
пришёл э в Россию Приходишь как будто
know you owe everyone or everyone wants to
знаешь ты всем должен или тебя все хотят
send you away You come Yes it is you come in
послать приходишь Да так и есть заходишь
you know how like this  as if in prison
знаешь как вот типа как будто в тюрьме
you want those now or you have to give them
ты захочешь сейчас те или ты должен дать
on the scoreboard or you will now be given statistics
в табло или Тебе сейчас дадут стати
really everywhere like this you go to the director you
реально везде так заходишь к директору
go the director looks at you like you’re
заходишь директор смотрит на вас как на
in Russia and you go into the transport Yes everyone
в России да в транспорт заходишь Да все
looks at each other like a conductor we look
смотрят вну друга как кондуктор смотрим
Let’s do everything in Russia  you know exactly,
Давайте всё в России именно знаешь
Man is a wolf to man, it’s just
Человек человеку волк просто
cruel Yes, in reality, the mentality is
жесть Да реально так и есть менталитет
completely different, you need to learn this
вообще абсолютно разный надо учить этот
English in short and go. And you, by the way, you
английский короче и ехать А вы Кстати вы
know chickpeas very poorly in English.
кстати английский знаете нут плохо очень
No, really. I’m interested in the
Нет реально Вот мне интересно вот по
sound of it. Try to count D to D
звучанию Попробуйте До Д посчитать
8 10 then 11 more  I wish I could remember
8 10 потом 11 ещё бы вспомнить
Now
Теперь
Alvin
Элвин
Elvin further 12
Элвин дальше 12
Oh, I don’t remember anymore, they actually taught this
Ох уже так не вспомню прям учили этому
But somehow you 12
Но уже как-то вы 12
on a 19 Yes
на а 19 Да
no and T Yes
нет а T Да
13 no yes - this is 14 A
13 нет да - это 14 А
then 14 15
потом 14 15
like Yes,
как Да
probably
наверное
16 correct 17
16 правильно 17
here
вот
20 zero niya Well, it’s normal, no
20 нулевые ния Ну нормально не
more or less the basic level is already there,
более-менее базовый уже уровень есть
you can improve it, that is, it’s like there’s
можно поправить да то есть типа там
something like, in short, you can talk to a girl, you
что-то по типу короче девочкой говорить
can talk to a girl, you can talk to a girl,
можно с девочкой говорить можно да
yes, that’s enough. The base base is just the most real, what’s really real,
реально то что вот ну вот реально
almost everyone knows  Well, this is the
практически кажды знает Ну это вот
school curriculum You have, yes, that
школьная программа У тебя есть да то
is, look right there, in order to live in
есть тут же смотри для того чтобы жить в
America you don’t have to know
Америке не обязательно там знать там
Future in the Past there, for example, yes, you have
Future in the Past там например да тебе
enough basic vocabulary, for example,
достаточно базовой лексики например вот
you have it, yes, that is, you need to repeat a little
у тебя она есть да то есть тебе немножко
and you  you will already
повторить и ты будешь уже
Well, well, just hold a specific
Ну Ну вот именно провести Вот конкретный
full-fledged dialogue Well, this is no longer this already
полноценный диалог Ну это уже нет это
We won’t be able to because, well, we know
уже Мы не сможем потому что ну мы знаем
Well, look when you stay here for example
Ну смотри когда ты побудешь тут например
uh a certain time yes You come to the
ээ определённое время да Приезжаешь да в
country and live there as if in the country That
страну и там живёт как бы в стране То
is, if  come to America you will
есть если приехать в Америку ты будешь
still no no you need to communicate in
всё равно нет нет тебе надо общаться на
this language and you learn it little by little
этом языке и ты его ну учишь потихонечку
yes by itself it
да само по себе оно так
goes like that you have to fly to America really it’s
идёт надо лететь в Америку реально это
just what everyone says in Russia in America America
просто все так говорят в России Америка
everything is bad there they are very jealous they are
там плохо всё очень там завидуют
jealous Yes yes  yes, because well, young people
завидуют Да да да потому что ну молодёжь
seem to know and fumble, they
как бы которая знает и шарит она
understand that it’s cool, namely those who were
понимает что это круто а именно те кто
still born in the USSR, well, they say that it’s
СССР ещё родились они Ну они говорят что
bad there, those who are in the Soviet of Deputies, they understand
там плохо те кто совдеп они понимают
a little, and young people fumble around that it’s really
немного а молодёжь шарит что там реально
cool there, it’s good.
круто там хорошо
Truth We must Accept everything American  Yes, there are
Правда Надо Прим всё американское Да там
computers, American operating
компьютеры американские операционные
systems, American telephone,
системы американские телефон
American Yes, this is generally incomprehensible
американский Да это вообще непонятно
Russia, we say America, but at the same time,
Россия мы говорим Америка но при этом у
every third iPhone in Russia has an iPhone
каждого третьего iPhone в России iPhone
that is America. Why don’t we have Russian
что Америка Почему у нас нету российских
phones, Russian components for the
телефонов российских компонентов для
computer, no Russian tablets,
компьютера нету планшетов российских
nothing like the richest country
нету ничего чего богатейшая вроде страна
people live  and technology No, they didn’t
люди живут и техники Нет с они не
come up with anything of their own Well, the auto industry is
придумали своего ничего Ну автопром
Russian, but what is it, what is it AvtoVAZ when
русский но что это что это АвтоВАЗ когда
there are already Chinese, now the
есть уже китайцы сейчас как вышли на
Germans entered the market BMW AB without
рынок немцы BMW АВ без подушек
airbags, some models Yes yes No, well,
безопасности некоторые модели Да да Не
Vesta new Yes, now if we take
ну Веста новая Да сейчас вот если брать
the newest one That is  but even then the price for
самый новый То есть но и то цены на
Vesta is 2.2 rubles Yes, for this money you can
весту 2.2 руб Да за эти деньги можно
get I don’t know BMW a good car Niva, a
взять Я не знаю BMW хорошую машину Нива
new Niva came out in Russia, yes Niva
вышла новая Нива у нас в России да Нива
Legend 2 million And in terms of quality Well, there are
Legend 2 млн А по качеству Ну там
700,000
700.000
edge two lyama for the Niva they ask for the
край два ляма за Ниву просят за
Niva yes yes 20  a few bucks just for a Niva,
Ниву да да 20 штук баксов просто за Ниву
for 20 bucks you can buy a foreign car,
за 20 штук баксов можно купить иномарку
of course it will be a used car, of course,
конечно она будет бэушная понятное дело
but no, well, you can even take a Hyundai
Но нет ну можно даже взять Hyundai
Solaris, the same K Rio Yes, for a d lama,
Solaris тот же самый K Rio Да за д ляма
and it will be much better than a
и это будет намного лучше нежели Нива
simply
просто
Russian Niva, as it were, well, we live in  In Russia,
Российская как бы ну да живём в России
we are patriots,
мы патриоты
but what are patriots? What does
но а патриоты в чём в чём Что значит
patriots mean? Patriot is that well, you should be
патриоты Патриот то что ну ты ты должен
proud of your
гордиться своей
country, in the sense that you should be
страной в смысле должен
proud because, well, you’re
гордиться потому что как бы ну ты
already a Patriot, but Prim,
уже но Прим
you understand What is the standard of living here?
ты понимаешь Какой тут уровень жизни то
For example,
что мы не то это получается Например
the worm he lives understands that this is all, but
глист он живёт понимает что это всё но
he’s kind of proud of him. Yes, it turns out because he was
он типа гордится им Да выходит потому
born here. Well, I can’t go out and
родился Ну я ж не могу вот выйти и
say America is cool, America is top, like,
сказать Америка круто Америка топ типа
because the whole public opinion is
потому что все общественное мнение
society,
общество
you just can’t do that
просто бы ты не можешь так сделать
about but in  the head of the Armed Forces is equal to the majority Who
про но в голове ВС равно большинство Кто
says Patriot Yes, but he understands that
говорит Патриот Да но он понимает что за
it’s better to live abroad than
границей лучше жить нежели
here ladies, damn it’s just that you shouldn’t
здесь дамы же просто блин надо не
attack other countries but invest
нападать на другие страны а вкладывать
money in your development Well, yes,
деньги в своё развитие Ну да дороги у
our roads are all broken, everything is built from
нас все разбиты э строится всё из
cheap materials, everything comes later
дешёвого строй материало всё потом
it’s collapsing, as it were, yes Really, well, there is such a
рушится как бы да Реально ну есть такое
thing, tell me, come on, they
всё скажи давай дальше детские площадки
don’t make playgrounds, hospitals don’t build them, as if they are
не делают больницы не строят как бы их
just renovating the old ones, and not everywhere
только ремонтируют старые и то не везде
and not always
и не всегда
Kiryukha is already tired of Kiryukha, he says, Let’s
Кирюха уже кирюхи надоела говорит Давай
turn it off Well, Kiryukha, I just
выключай Ну Кирюха просто как бы я вот
like to talk like this  and he Kiryukha is
люблю вот так пообщаться а он Кирюха
just shocked by the fact that in short
просто в шоке от того что короче се у
he has depression now for a week after
него депрессия теперь неделю будет после
this after
это после
America Kiryukha Kiryukha look I’ll
Америки Кирюха Кирюха смотри я тебе
tell you the recipe look In short after this
скажу рецепт посмотри Короче после этого
stress look how people in Cuba
стресса посмотрите как люди на Кубе
live there in short the salary is generally something like
живут там короче зарплата вообще что-то
19 dollars Yes you  it’s
19 долларов Да тебе полегчает
hard to feel better when I came here to
тяжело вос Я когда приехал сюда в
California for the first time, I felt like you
Калифорнию первый раз я себя ощущал
know, well, from Rostov to California You
понимаешь ну с Ростова в Калифорнию Ты
look at people with such salaries, you and they
смотришь люди с такими зарплатами ты и
ask you How much did you have
тебя спрашивают А сколько у тебя было
there and you’re like that And when I’m wild later I’ll
там и ты такой А я когда диком поже
tell you how homeless people get paid here  2000
скажет как у нас бездомные получают 2000
from
от
as a type and when you say that you
как типа и когда ты говоришь что ты там
worked there for 200 dollars in Rostov Yes they are
работал за 200 долларов в Ростове Да они
like what did you do there you understand yes
такие типа что ты там делал понимаешь да
But how to live how to live simply that is they
А как жить как жить просто то есть они
They don’t believe that for that kind of money someone
Они не верят Что за такие деньги кто-то
can even
может вообще
work for real  so it is, in short, Kiryukha
работать льно так и есть короче Кирюха
is extinguished, in short, Kiryukha is going to California, we
потух короче Кирюха в Калифорнию нам
have to go anyway, I’m already thinking about what kind of
надо ехать по-любому я уже думаю какие
tickets I’m going to Aal now. What to take?
билеты сейчас на Аал захожу Что взять Да
No, I really need to move around. But
нет реально надо перемещаться Но это
first, I need to finish my studies here,
надо сначала с учёбой тут закончить этот
get this education, and then fly.
образование получить И уже потом лететь
What about
А что
education?  this one is not listed
образование вот это оно не котируется
there in Russia oh in America Well, at least
там в России ой в Америке А ну хотя бы
get an average Well, just so that it
среднее получить Ну просто чтобы
’s all the same, I understand something okay, let’s
было всё равно что-то понял хорошо
run Let’s all church Don’t be bored with everything And
побегу Давайте Всё кирха Не скучай всё И
remember what you know, here’s the American dream
помни что знаешь вот Американская мечта
that everyone can achieve anything, let’s
что каждый может достичь всего давай
really Thank you  thank you for the dialogue See you
реально Спасибо вам за диалог До
[laughs]
[смех]
bye like subscribe and comment Let's
свидания лайк подписка и комент Давайте
and friends send off the Californian bashing, the
и друзья скиньте й калифорнийский разнос
guys are just so shocked they
просто пацаны такие в шоке всю
gave away all the ins and outs of our Russian
подноготную выдали российскую у нас
roads, shmags, this is a total mess Kiryukha is
дороги шмаги это вообще капец Кирюха
generally depressed Let's subscribe to
вообще в депрессии Давайте подписались
Vikova and make a video of someone who won't spoil that one
викова и пошили видос хто не зробить той
in the coming days they will also be born in
буде в наступному жит народиться тоже в
Russia Although not Russia will not
Росии Хотя не Росии не буде вона
fall apart Glory to Ukraine letter to my
развалиться Слава украини пись на мий
Telegram directly at once axis VN
Telegram прямо зараз ось ВН
apok tse more and more respectfully YouTube taking
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through the scum of ODS in your ban and I do
нас через скарг ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
n’t show too many videos to people often don’t
багато видео не показую людям вчасно не
show information  about streaming Tom, for this
показуе информация про стрими Тому для
purpose, we need to write a Mali operational link
того щоб ми Мали оперативний звязок
right away and while there in Telegra
пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в телегра
okrim video schezh tsikava and kos
окрим видео ще теж цикава и кос
information and we are responsible for you trimati
информация и мы повинни з вами тримати
postiyny operational link independantly in
постийний оперативный звязок незалежно в
that chi show you about it YouTube Glory to
того чи покаже вам про це YouTube Слава
Ukraine
Украине
subscribe L
подпишись L